Guide to the Leah Salisbury Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Leah Salisbury Papers
1925-1975.
Salisbury, Leah Javne, 1893-1975.
149 linear ft. (ca. 185,000 items in 327 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079290
Biographical Note
Literary and theatrical agent.
Scope and Content
Papers of Leah Goldstein Javne Salisbury, consisting of correspondence, contracts, scripts, and financial records. Among the correspondents are Christopher Fry, William Gibson, Eugène Ionesco, Dorothy Parker, S.J. Perelman, and Stark Young.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 8 series:
Series I. Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
Series III: Arranged Correspondence and Manuscripts
Series IV: Financial Records
Series V: Readers' Reports
Series VI: Printed Material
Series VII: Card Files
Series VIII: Reviews and Publicity
Subjects
Fry, Christopher, 1907-2005.; Gibson, William, 1914-2008.; Ionesco, Eugène.; Parker, Dorothy, 1893-1967.; Perelman, S. J. (Sidney Joseph), 1904-1979.; Young, Stark, 1881-1963.; Authors.; Literature publishing.; Theater.; Scripts.; Literary agents.; Theatrical agents.; Women in the theater.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
M-59 Salisbury, Leah Gift
Alternate Formats
William Goyen letters and Dorothy Parker manuscripts are on microfilm.
- Series I. Cataloged Correspondence
  - Akins, Zoe
  - Albee, Edward Franklin
  - Albert, Eddie
  - Allen, Fred
  - Ames, Winthrop
  - Amiel, Denys Roch Marie Guillaume
  - Anderson, Judith
  - Anderson, Maxwell
  - Armstrong, Anthony
  - Anouilh, Jean
  - Axelrod, George
  - Bankhead, Tallulah
  - Barlow, Samuel Latham Mitchill
  - Beebe, Elswyth Thane
  - Behrman, Samuel Nathaniel
  - Belasco, David
  - Bellamy, Ralph
  - Bennett, Richard
  - Benson, Sally
  - Bergman, Ingrid
  - Best, Edna
  - Bire, Lajos
  - Blackburn, Paul
  - Bolton, Guy
  - Bok, Curtis
  - Booth, Shirley
  - Bourjaily, Vance
  - Braddell, Maurice
  - Brand, Millen
  - Brent, Romney
  - Brook, Clive
  - Burnett, Whit
  - Burrows, Abe
  - Burton, Richard
  - Cagney, James
  - Camus, Albert
  - Cane, Melville Henry
  - Cantor, Eddie
  - Christians, Mady
  - Ciardi, John
  - Clair, Rene
  - Clouzot, Henri-Georges
  - Coburn, Charles
  - Cohan, George Michael
  - Collier, Constance
  - Connelly, Marc
  - Cooper, Gladys
  - Cooper, Violet Kemble
  - Copeland, Royal Samuel
  - Cornell, Katharine
  - Costain, Thomas Bertram
  - Cronyn, Hume
  - Crouse, Russel
  - Cullen, Countee
  - Dahl, Ronald
  - Dane, Clemence
  - Davidson, Jo
  - Davis, Bette
  - Day, Dorothy
  - De Havilland, Olivia Mary
  - Deighton, Len
  - Dell, Berta-Marie Gage (Mrs Floyd)
  - Dell, Floyd
  - Delmar, Vina
  - De Mille, Agnes George
  - Dietz, Howard
  - Dowling, Eddie
  - Drake, Alfred
  - Ehrenberg, Ilya
  - Eichelberger, Clark Mell
  - Ernst, Morris Leopold
  - Evans, Maurice
  - Ferrer, Jose
  - Ferrer, Mel
  - Fontaine, Joan
  - Fry, Christopher
  - Gardiner, Reginald
  - Garfield, John
  - Garnett, David
  - Gibson, William
  - Gide, André
  - Gielgud, John
  - Goddard, Paulette
  - Gold, Michael
  - Gorer, Geoffrey
  - Goyen William
  - Greenfell, Joyce
  - Guiness, Alec
  - Gewnn, Edmund
  - Hammerstein, Oscar, II
  - Hampden, Walter
  - Handy, William Christopher
  - Hansberry, Lorraine
  - Hart, Moss
  - Hellman, Lillian
  - Helpmann, Robert Murray
  - Hepburn, Katharine
  - Hiller, Wendy
  - Hitchcock, Alfred
  - Hollander, John
  - Horgan Paul
  - Horton, Edward Everett
  - Hughes, Langston
  - Ingersoll, Ralph McAllister
  - Ionesco, Eugene
  - Johnson, Nunally
  - Kanin, Garson
  - Kantor, MacKinley
  - Karolyi, Catharine Andrassy, Countess
  - Kaufman, Geoge S.
  - Kazan, Elia
  - Kelly, Gene
  - Kern, Jerome
  - Kimbrough, Emily
  - King, Dennis
  - Knight, Eric
  - Kramm, Joseph
  - Kruger, Otto
  - Lawrence, Gertrude
  - La Gallienne, Eva
  - Lehrer, Thomas Andrew
  - Leigh, Vivien
  - Lenya, Lotte
  - Lewis, Sinclair
  - Lindsay, Howard
  - Littlewood, Jean Maud
  - Lunt, Alfred
  - Macgowan, Kenneth
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - Mantle, Burns
  - March, Fredric
  - Martin, Mary
  - Marx, "Groucho" Julius
  - Massey, Raymond
  - Maugman, Robin
  - Maurois, Andre
  - Meloney, William Brown
  - Menen, Aubrey
  - Merrill, Gary
  - Mielziner, Jo
  - Mitchell, Thomas
  - Morley, Christopher
  - Muni, Paul
  - Nash, Ogden
  - Nathan, George Jean
  - Nazimova, Alla
  - Nugent, Elliott
  - Olivier, Laurence Kerr, Baron Oliver
  - Pagnol, Marcel Paul
  - Parker, Dorothy
  - Peck, Gregory
  - Perelman, Sidney Joseph
  - Perkins, Maxwell Evarts
  - Pickford, Mary
  - Power, Tyrone
  - Quintere, Jose
  - Ratoff, Gregory
  - Rice, Elmer
  - Robinson, Edward G.
  - Robson, Flora
  - Rodgers, Richard
  - Rosenberg, James Naumberg
  - Ross, Harold Wallace
  - Rosten, Nonnan
  - Rothschild, (Baron) Philippe Georges
  - Russell, Anna
  - Rysking, Morrie
  - Schildkraut, Joseph
  - Schuster, Max Lincoln
  - Schwartz, Maurice
  - Sheean, Diana Forbes-Robertson (Mrs Vincent)
  - Sherwood, Robert E.
  - Siegmeister, Elie
  - Smith, Edgar Valentine
  - Spewack, Sam & Bella
  - Stern, Gladys Bronwyn
  - Stewart, James
  - Stickney, Dorothy
  - Stoppard, Tom
  - Storey, David Malcolm
  - Swallow, Alan
  - Tabori, Paul
  - Tandy, Jessica
  - Tone, Franchot
  - Treacher, Arthur
  - Tucker, Sophie
  - Untermeyer, Louis
  - Vanderbilt, Amy
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem
  - Walker, James J.
  - Wallach, Eli
  - Wanamaker, Sam
  - Waters, Ethel br>Webb, Clifton
  - Webster, Margaret
  - Weill, Kurt
  - Weitzkorn, Louis
  - Welles, Orson
  - Wexley, John
  - Wheelock, John Hall
  - Whiteside, Walker
  - Wilder, Thornton
  - Williams, Emlyn
  - Willson, Meredith
  - Winslow, Thyra Samter
  - Wise, Stephen Samuel
  - Wood, Peggy
  - Woolf, Leonard
  - Wouk, Herman
  - Wynn, Ed
  - Young, Stark
- Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
  - Atkins, Zoe
  - Algren, Nelson
  - Anderson, Maxwell
  - Armstrong, Anthony
  - Barnes, Djuna Chappell
  - Beach, Rex Ellingwood
  - Bercovici, Konrad
  - Bernstein, Henry
  - Best, Edna
  - Brent, Romney
  - Cain, James Mallahan
  - Connelly, Marc
  - Cullen, Countee
  - Dane, Clemence
  - Day, Dorothy
  - Delmar, Vina
  - Dietz, Howard
  - Drew, Elizabeth
  - Erskine, John
  - Fast, Howard
  - Ferrer, Jose
  - Freuchen, Peter
  - Fry, Christopher
  - Gibson, William
  - Godden, Jon
  - Hanley, William
  - Hardwicke, (Sir) Cedric
  - Hirschfeld, Albert
  - Horgan, Paul.
  - Hughes, Langsbon
  - Ionesco, Eugene
  - Jameson, Storm
  - Kaufman George S.
  - King, Alexander
  - Kramm, Joseph
  - Laughton, Charles
  - Leven, Meyer
  - Masefield, John
  - Maugham, Robin
  - Millay, Kathleen Kalloch
  - Nash, Ogden
  - Nathan, Robert
  - Nichols, Beverly
  - Nugent, Elliott
  - Parker, Dorothy
  - Perelman, Sidney Joseph
  - Phillpotts, Eden
  - Priestley, John Boynton
  - Rosten, Norman
  - Roth, Philip
  - Russell, Rosalind
  - Smith, Betty
  - Steinbeck, John
  - Street, Julian
  - Tarkington, Booth
  - Tolstoi, Alexei Nikolaevitch
  - Untermeyer, Louis
  - Vildrac, Charles
  - Vonnegut, Kurt, Jr.
  - Wallace, Irving
  - Weitzenkorn, Louis
  - Welles, Orson
  - Wexley, John
  - Wharton, Edith Newbold Jones
  - White, Patrick
  - Wolfe, Thomas Clayton
  - Young, Stark
- Series III: Arranged Correspondence and Manuscripts
  - Aberg, Gilbert (Box 1)
  - Actors and Actresses (Box 1)
  - Actors' Studio, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Adams, Bown (Box 1)
  - Adams, James F. (Box 1)
  - Adelman, Louis C. (Box 1)
  - Adler, Marjorie Duhan (Box 1)
  - Agents: U.S. & Foreign (Box 2-7)
  - Agents: U.S. & Foreign (Box 8)
  - Christopher Mann Ltd. (Box 8)
  - Aiken, W. Appleton (Box 9)
  - Akins, Zoe (Box 9)
  - Albee, Edward (Box 9)
  - Albertsson, Kristjan (Box 9)
  - Alexander, C.K. (Box 9)
  - Alzamora, Lucia (Box 9)
  - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (Box 9)
  - American Playwrights Theatre (Box 9)
  - American Theatre Wing (& Stage Door Canteen) (Box 9)
  - Andrews, Bert (Box 9)
  - Andrews, Ellen (Box 9)
  - Anthony, Carol K. (Box 9)
  - Anthony, Norman (Box 9)
  - Anton, Nathan (Don Rozi Anton) (Box 9)
  - Apartment 6F, Inc. (Box 9)
  - Apsey, Ruby Lloyd (Box 9)
  - Arden, Cecil (Box 9)
  - Arent, Arthur (Box 9)
  - Armstrong, Anthony (Box 10 & 11)
  - Aronson, Boris (Box 12)
  - Arthur, Robert (Box 12)
  - Ash, Edward Eric (Box 12)
  - Ashmore, Peter (Box 12)
  - Atkinson, Brooks Correspondence (Box 13&14)
  - Atkinson, Brooks Royalty Statements; Mss. (Box 15)
  - Atkinson, Brooks Mss. (Box 16)
  - Atkinson, Brooks Proofs & Printed Materials (Box 18)
  - Atkinson, Oriana (Box 19)
  - Atkinson, Oriana - (2) (Box 20)
  - Atkinson, T. (Box 21)
  - The Author Guild, Inc. (Box 21)
  - Axelson, Mary McDougal (Box 21)
  - Aylen, Peter (Box 21)
  - Baehr, Nicholas F. (Box 21)
  - Baer, Richard (Box 21)
  - Bailey, Don Berman (Box 21)
  - Bailey, Stewart C. (Box 21)
  - Bailey, Temple (Box 21)
  - Baker, Herbert (Box 21)
  - Bamberger, Theron (Box 21)
  - Banbury, Frith (Box 21)
  - Barber, Benjamin R. (Box 21)
  - Barber, Philip Willson (Box 21)
  - Barbour, June (Box 21)
  - Barnouw, Erik (Box 21)
  - Barton, Trumbull (Box 21)
  - Bass, Milton R. (Box 21)
  - Bayley, Jefferson (Box 21)
  - Beauchamp, Guy & Michael Pertwee (Box 22)
  - Beaumont, Comyns (Box 22)
  - Becall, Lauren (Box 22)
  - Becker, Ivan Lawrence (Box 22)
  - Becker, John F. (Box 22)
  - Becker, Lester (Box 22)
  - Beckett, Samuel (Box 22)
  - Beebe, Elswyth Thane Ricker (Mrs. William) (Box 22)
  - Benedictus, David (Box 22)
  - Bennett, Dorothy Cheston (Box 22)
  - Bercovici, Leonardo (Box 22)
  - Berg, Lee & Alfred Golden (Box 22)
  - Berger, Maurice (Box 22)
  - Bergman, Jules (Box 22)
  - Bernard, Kenneth (Box 22)
  - Berryman, John (Henry Ellis) (Box 22)
  - Besoyan, Rick (Box 22)
  - Best, Charles (Box 22)
  - Betts, A.A. (Box 22)
  - Bigelow, Otis Correspondence (Box 23)
  - Bigelow, Otis Correspondence; Mss.:1963-1972; "Peacock Season" & "Prevalence of Mrs. Seal" l964-1972 "Cinderella" & "Whoever Finds This Bottle" 1963-1971 "Peacock Season" & "Giant's Dance" 1964-1968 (Box 24)
  - Bigelow, Otis Mss. (Box 25)
  - Bigelow, Sylvia (Box 26)
  - Bird, Edward (Box 26)
  - Brinkrant, Samuel (Box 26)
  - Biro, Lajos (Box 26)
  - Birstein, Ann (Box 26)
  - Bishop, Christopher (Box 26)
  - Black, Hilda (Box 26)
  - Black, Jean Ferguson (Box 26)
  - Black, Kitty (Box 27)
  - Blane, Ralph & Hush Martin (Box 28)
  - Blankner, Frederika (Box 28)
  - Bliss, Mason (Box 28)
  - Bliven, R.M. (Box 28)
  - Blocki, Fritz (Box 28)
  - Bloom, Phillip (Box 28)
  - Bobb, Ralph (Box 28)
  - Boehm, David (Box 28)
  - Bok, Curtis (Box 28)
  - Boland, Bridget (Box 28)
  - Bolton, Muriel Ray (Box 28)
  - Bone, Harold N. (Box 28)
  - Bonnard, Robert Andrew (Box 28)
  - Boretz, Allen (Box 28)
  - Borg, Victor (Box 28)
  - Boruff, John Correspondence (Box 29 & 30)
  - Boruff, John Mss. (Box 31 & 32)
  - Boss, B. Duncan ("Ward Duncan") (Box 33)
  - Bossom, I. Bernard (Box 33)
  - Bowen, John (Box 33)
  - Bowen-Jones, W.W. (Terry) (Box 33)
  - Box, Sydney & Muriel Baker Box (Box 33)
  - Boyer, Josephine (Box 33)
  - Braddell, Maurice (Box 33)
  - Bradlee, Benjamin C. & Peter Wyden (Box 33)
  - Bradshaw, George Correspondence (Box 34-38)
  - Bradshaw, George Mss. & Royalty Statements (Box 39)
  - Brann, Vincent (Box 40)
  - Brecher, Eve (Box 40)
  - Breer Charles Patrick (Box 40)
  - Brenner, Raymond Paul (Box 40)
  - Brent, Romney - 1 (Box 40)
  - Brent, Romney - 2 (Box 41)
  - Bricker, Herschel L. (Box 41)
  - Bridle, James "Mr. Boifry" (Box 41)
  - Briggs, Beryl B. (Box 41)
  - Briggs, Hazel F. (Box 41)
  - Bright, John (Box 41)
  - Briskin, Jacqueline (Box 41)
  - Brisman, Chain (Box 41)
  - Broadway/Off-Broadway - General (Box 42)
  - Brook, Beatrice (Box 42)
  - Brooks, John (Box 42)
  - Brossard, Chandler (Box 42)
  - Brown, Beth (Box 42)
  - Brown, Michael Martin (Box 42)
  - Brown, Russell Aplin (Box 42)
  - Browner, Richard (Box 42)
  - Brune, Gabrielle (Box 42)
  - Bruno, Tony (Box 42)
  - Buchman Harold "Snafu" (Box 42)
  - Buermann, Howard R. (Box 42)
  - Bullins, Edward (Box 42)
  - Bullock, Turner - 1 (Box 42)
  - Bullock, Turner - 2 (Box 43)
  - Burger, Eric (Box 44)
  - Burrell, John (Box 44)
  - Burton, Lilliam Krieger (Box 44)
  - Burton, Russell (Box 44)
  - Butman, Robert (Box 44)
  - Buttitta, Anthony (Box 44)
  - Calamar, Doris (Box 44)
  - Callen, Harold "The Bashsul Genius" (Box 44)
  - Campbell, Alan & Robert Stevenson (Box 44)
  - Campbell, Lawton (Box 45)
  - Campbell-Duncan, H. (Box 45)
  - Camus, Albert (Box 45)
  - Canfield, Mary Cass & Ethel Borden (Box 45)
  - Cantor, Eli (Box 45)
  - Garb, David (Box 45)
  - Cardozo, P.S. - 1 (Box 46)
  - Cardozo P.S. - 2 (Box 47)
  - Carlisle, H.G. (Box 47)
  - Carison, Richard (Box 48 & 49)
  - Carole, Joseph (Box 50)
  - Carrington, Elaine (Box 50)
  - Carroll, Claire (Box 50)
  - Carro, Burnell (Box 50)
  - Carruthers, Richard (Box 50)
  - Carson, Robert (Box 50)
  - Carter, Myra (Box 50)
  - Cates, Norma (Box 50)
  - Cavanagh, A. Maura & Howell Price (Box 50)
  - Chamberlin, Norwood (Box 50)
  - Cherney, David (Box 50)
  - Chethan - Strode, Warren (Box 50)
  - Child, Nellise (Box 50)
  - Chodorov, Edward (Box 50)
  - Christopher, Greg (Box 50)
  - Clark, Kenneth R. (Box 50)
  - Clavell, J Correspondence: --Countdown (W.A) 1958-1961 --Refusals 1958-1965 --General 1958-1971 --Countdown (W.A) 1960-1966 --King Rat Publishers 1960-1966 --King Rat Film 1961-1966 --King Rat Scandinavia 1962-1964 --King Rat France 1962-1965 --King Rat Holland 1962-1965 --King Rat U.K. 1962-1967 --King Rat Germany 1962-1967 (Box 51)
  - Clavell, James Correspondence: --King Rat Foreign 1962-68 --A Children's Story 1963-68 --Tai Pan Film 1964-66 --Tai Pan Atheneum-Dell 1964-66 --Tai Pan Germany 1964-68 --Perfect Timing 1964-69 --Tai Pan U..K. 1964-72 --Tai Pan France 1965-66 --A Children's Story Drama 1965-68 --Tai Pan FiJin 1965-69 --A Children's Story TV 1966 --Tai Pan Foreign 1966-67 --Tai Pan Publicity 1966-67 --Tai Pan Scandinavia 1966-67 --Tai Pan Holland 1956-67 --Countdown 1966-68 --Tai Pan Spain & Portugal 1966-69 --Tai Pan Italy 1967 -- Royalty Statements (Box 52)
  - Clavell, J Mss. (Box 53)
  - Clavell, James Mss. "King Rat" (Box 54-55)
  - Clavell, James Mss. "Shogun" (Box 56-57)
  - Clemens, LeRoy & John B. Hymer (Box 58)
  - Clement, Victor (Box 58)
  - Clift, Denison (Box 58)
  - Cobin, Harold (Box 58)
  - Coffelt, Elizabeth (Box 58)
  - Cohen, G. Lesley (Box 58)
  - Cole, Joseph H. (Box 58)
  - Colet, Maxine H. (Box 58)
  - Collins, R. Douglas (Box 58)
  - Colton, Edward E. (Box 58)
  - Community Theaters (Box 58)
  - Comstock, Howard Warren & James Edward Grant (Box 58)
  - Conger, Gwynn & Nathaniel Benchley (Box 58)
  - Conger, Trista (Box 58)
  - Conklin, William B. (Box 58)
  - Conkling, Wilbur S. (Box 58)
  - Connell, Louise Fox (Box 58)
  - Connelly, Marc (Box 58)
  - Conrad, Sybil (Box 58)
  - Contests (Box 58)
  - Contracts - samples (Box 58)
  - Cook, A.M. (Box 58)
  - Cooper, Madison A., Jr. (Box 58)
  - Copito, Benjamin (Box 58)
  - Copyright - Mexico (Box 58)
  - Cornell, Cameron (Box 58)
  - Corpening, Sara (Box 58)
  - Corwin, Norman Correspondence (Box 59 & 60)
  - Corwin, Norman Correspondence: --The Rivalry 1955-60 --1958-67 --The Rivalry Amateur Rights 1952 --Evening With Carl Sandberg 1959 --The Rivalry 1959-63 --The Rivalry l959-68 --World of Carl Sandburg 1960-68 --World of Carl Sandburg 1960-69 --World of Carl Sandberg Publication 1960-69 --The Hyphen 1961-67 --World of Carl Sandburg TV/Radio 1962 --World of Carl Sandburg NET-TV 1964 --The Hyphen 1966-1968 (Box 61)
  - Corwin, Norman Correspondence, Mss. Contracts, etc. (Box 62)
  - Costello, Don (Box 63)
  - Cotten, Joseph (1) (Box 63)
  - Cotten, Joseph (2) (Box 64)
  - Coughlan, Frank (Box 64)
  - Cowan, Percival E. (Box 64)
  - Coward, Noel (Box 64)
  - Cowen, Willaiam Joyce (Box 64)
  - Crabtree, Paul J. (Box 65)
  - Crandall, Edward (Box 66)
  - Creed, Will (Box 66)
  - Crimmins, Edward C. (Box 66)
  - Crockett, Otway (Box 66)
  - Cullen, Countee & Arna Bontemps (Box 67-68)
  - Cummings, Constance (Box 69)
  - Cuza, Joseph A. (Box 69)
  - Dachs, David & Julie Mandel (Box 69)
  - Dale, James (Box 69)
  - Darymple, Jean (Box 69)
  - Danico, Jim (Box 70)
  - Dane, Clemence (Box 70)
  - Daniels, James R. (Box 70)
  - Davidson, Madeline (Box 70)
  - Davidson, Michael (Box 70)
  - Dawn, Hazel (Box 70)
  - Day, Price (Box 70)
  - DeFelice, James (Box 70)
  - DeHartog, Jan Correspondence (Box 71-74)
  - DeHartog, Jan The Fourposter 1958-1964 The Fourposter Amateur 1958-1966 The Little Ark 1958-1970 The Fourposter 1959-1965 The Fourposter Inquiries 1959-1964 The Inspector 1959-1962 Waters of the New World 1959-1967 (Box 75)
  - DeHartog, Jan William & Mary 1959-1963 The Fourposter - Musical 1960-1963 The Fourposter - readings & Reviews 1960-1963 The Artist 1962-71 The Hospital 1964 I do, I do 1965-70 I do, I do - Foreign 1965-68 The Captain 1966-69 The Children 1969 I do, I do England 1963-70 I do, I do Tour 1968 (Box 76)
  - DeHartog, Jan Mss., Clippings, etc .: --The Artist --The Captain --The Children --Death of a Rat --The Distant Shore (Box 77)
  - DeHartog, Jan Mss., Clippings, etc. "The Fourposter" (Box 78)
  - DeHartog, Jan Mss., Clippings, etc.: --The Glory of the Sea --The Greatest Gift We Can Give... --Holland's Glory --The Hospital (Box 79)
  - DeHartog, Jan Mss., Clippings, etc.: --I do, I do --The Inspector (Box 80)
  - DeHartog, Jan Mss. Clippings, etc. --The Peaceable Kingdom (Box 81-83)
  - DeHartog, Jan Mss. Clippings, etc. --The Peaceable Kingdom --Robinson Crusoe in Florida --Saling Ships --A Sailor's Life --Ship's Company --Skipper Next to God (Box 84)
  - DeHartog, Ja Mss., Clippings, etc.: --The Spiral Road --Stella --This Time Tomorrow --Untergang der "Freiheit" --The Waters of the New World --The Young Bass of Outstanding Volume --A Younr Sailor's Companion (Box 85)
  - DeHartog, Jan Royalty Statements (Box 86)
  - Deigaard, Kent (Box 87)
  - Dekker, Albert (Box 87)
  - "Delafield, E.M." (Edmee Elizabeth Monica de La Pasture Dashwood) (Box 87)
  - Delderfield, Ronald Frederick (Box 87)
  - DeLeon, Jack (Box 87)
  - Dell, Marjorie (Box 87)
  - Debnan, David (Box 87)
  - Delman, Gray (Box 87)
  - Delmar, Vina (Box 88 & 89)
  - Deni, Conrad (Box 90)
  - Denicoff, Marvin (Box 90)
  - Denker & Berkey "Time Limit" (Box 90)
  - DePinna, Connie (Box 90)
  - Deutsch, Helen (Box 90)
  - DiBenedetto, AA (Box 90)
  - Dilmen, Gungor (Box 90)
  - Dineen, John (Box 90)
  - Directors (Box 90)
  - Disher, Leo (Box 90)
  - Doctorow, E. L. (Box 90)
  - Dolan, Frank (Box 90)
  - Donavan, Hobart (Box 90)
  - Donovan, James A. (Box 90)
  - Dorfman, Nat. N. (Box 90)
  - Doud, Earle (Box 90)
  - Dowell, John (Box 90)
  - Drakent, Eugene A. (Box 90)
  - The Dramatic Publishing Company (Box 90)
  - The Dramatists Guild, Inc. (Box 90)
  - Dramatists Play Service, Inc. (Box 90)
  - Drew, Elizabeth (Box 90)
  - Driver, Donald (Box 90)
  - Dryselius, Anna (Box 90)
  - Dude, Florence (Box 91)
  - Duff, Warren & Oscar Millard The Soft Sell (Box 91)
  - Duncan, Ronald (Box 91)
  - Dundy, Elaine (Box 91)
  - Dunham, Katherine (Box 91)
  - Dunkin, William S. (Box 91)
  - Dunn, Caesar (Box 91)
  - Dunn, Edward D. (Box 91)
  - Dunn, Francis P. (Box 91)
  - Dunning, Philip (Box 91)
  - D'Usseau, Arnaud & James Gow Correspondence (Box 92-95)
  - D'Usseau, Arnaud & James Gow Manuscripts, Clippings, etc. (Box 96-98)
  - D'Usseau, Arnaud & James Gow Manuscripts, Clippings, etc.: "Deep Are The Roots" (Box 99)
  - D'Usseau, Arnaud & James Gow Royalty Statements (Box 100)
  - D'Usseau, Leon (Box 101)
  - Dyment, Clifford (Box 101)
  - Eardley, Carl (Box 101)
  - Easterlin, Malcolm (Box 101)
  - Eastman, Ida Rauh (Box 101)
  - Eaton, William (Box 101)
  - Ebenstein, Morris (Box 101)
  - Edgar, Wendell (Box 101)
  - Ehrenman, Howard Norman (Box 101)
  - Ehrlich, Milton (Box 101)
  - Elhart, Earl W. (Box 101)
  - Eliscu, Edward (Box 101)
  - Elliott, Denholm (Box 101)
  - Ellis, Daniel (Box 101)
  - Ellis, David (Box 101)
  - Ellis, Ernest (Box 101)
  - Ellison, Ada (Box 101)
  - Emmons, Betsy (Box 101)
  - Engar, Keith M. (Box 101)
  - England, Robert (Box 101)
  - Englehart, Jean (Box 101)
  - Englund, Ken (Box 101)
  - Ensana, Joel A. (Box 101)
  - Ettlinger, Don (Box 101)
  - Ettlinger, Don Mss (Box 102)
  - Eunson, Dale & Katherine (Box 103)
  - Evans, Franklin T. (Box 103)
  - Evslin, Bernard (Box 103)
  - Fahy, William (Box 103)
  - Fales, Nancy (Box 103)
  - Farah, Ted (Box 103)
  - Farjeon, Eleanor & Herbert (Box 103)
  - Farnsworth, Clyde A. (Box 103)
  - Farrell, Lura B. (Box 103)
  - Farris, Gloria (Box 103)
  - Fedoroff, Alexander (Box 104)
  - Feldman, David (Box 104)
  - Ferguson, Charles W. (Box 104)
  - Field, Filip (Box 105)
  - Fields, Len (Box 105)
  - Figueiredo, Guilherme (Box 105)
  - Filler, Agnes Emberson (Box 105)
  - Firbank, Ronald (Box 105)
  - Fisher, Steve (Box 105)
  - Fitzgerald, Edith (Box 105)
  - Fleming, Thomas, J (Box 105)
  - Fliegler, Irving (Box 105)
  - Flint, Eva Kay (Eva K. Finkelstein) (Box 105)
  - Foley, Duncan K. (Box 106)
  - Forbes, John (Box 106)
  - Ford, Thomas I. (Box 106)
  - The Ford Foundation (Box 106)
  - Foreign Theater, Publishers, Agents, Attorneys, etc. (Box 106)
  - Foreman, Carl (Box 106)
  - Foreman, Richard (Box 106)
  - Forster, Dory (Box 106)
  - Foster, Joseph (Box 106)
  - Foulston, Pauline (Box 106)
  - Fowle, Donald Wallace (Box 106)
  - Fradkin, Jane E. (Box 106)
  - Fraenkel, Helene (Box 106)
  - Frances, Charlotte (Box 106)
  - Freedley, Vinton (Box 106)
  - Freedman, Melvin H. (Box 106)
  - Freeman, Charles K. (Box 106)
  - Freeman, Don (Box 106)
  - Freeman, Lucy (Box 106)
  - Freund, Philip (Box 106)
  - Fried, Emanuel J. (Box 106)
  - Friedman, Joel J. (Box 106)
  - Friedman, Roy (Box 106)
  - Fruchter, Norman (Box 106)
  - Fry, Christopher Correspondence (Box 107-113)
  - Fry, Christopher Correspondence: --Venus Observed 1958-66 --The Firstborn 1956-66 --Oxford Press Anthologies 1957-68 --Adza Vincent Ltd. 1958-66 --Boy With A Cart l958-62 --Duel of Angels 1959-61 --Editors - Rejections 1958-64 --The Lady's Not For Burning 1958-1970 (Box 114)
  - Fry, Christopher Correspondence: --The Lark 1958-1966 --A Phoenix Too Frequent 1958-1966 --Ring Aroung The Moon 1958-1968 --Sleep of Prisioners 1958-1968 --Thor, With Angels 1958-1963 --Tiger At The Gates 1958-1969 --Curtmantle 1960-1968 --Judith 1961-1963 --A Yard of Sun 1970-1971 (Box 115)
  - Fry, Christopher Mss., Clippings, etc. (Box 116-118)
  - Fry, Christopher Royalty Statements (Box 119-120)
  - Fundaburk, Emma Lila (Box 121)
  - Furness, Mark ("Frank Barbara") (Box 121)
  - Gabrielson, Frank (Box 122-124)
  - Gagliano, Frank (Box 125)
  - Gann, Ernest (Box 125)
  - Garcia, Eduardo (Box 125)
  - Gard, Robert E. (Box 125)
  - Garnett, David (Box 125)
  - Garrett, Helen (Box 125)
  - Gassner, John (Box 125)
  - Gaston, Ken (Box 125)
  - Gearon, John ("John Flagg") (Box 125)
  - Gebler, Ernest (Box 125)
  - Geffen, Joy (Box 125)
  - Gehman, Clarence H. (Box 125)
  - Geiger, Milton (Box 126)
  - Gerry, Roger (Box 127)
  - Gerstine, John (Box 127)
  - Giblin, James (Box 127)
  - Gibney, Sheridan & Katrin (Box 127)
  - Gibson, Roberta (Box 127)
  - Gibson, William Correspondence (Box 128-130)